Guide to the Charles Kent Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Correspondence, 1815-1918; Series I; 0.81; (2 boxes)
  - GENERAL CORRESPONDENCE
    - Unidentified correspondents
      - 6 ALS to CK, 1875-95, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 87)
      - Empty envelopes, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 88)
  - COPIES OF LETTERS TO CHARLES KENT
    - Manuscript notebook containing copies of letters to CK from Charles Dickens, Harrison Ainsworth and Wilkie Collins (Box 2, Folder 89)
  - THIRD-PARTY CORRESPONDENCE
    - Blanchard, Caroline
      - ALS to Harry, 1896 Jan (Box 2, Folder 90)
    - Capel, T. J. (Thomas John), 1836-1911
      - ALS to Bishop Fenton; Arno, Cal., 1906 Oct 30 (Box 2, Folder 91)
        Protesting discussion of him in Father Kent's planned biography of Cardinal Manning. With copies of two letters by J. H. Rutherford-Smith and G. B. Malleson in support of his claims
    - Evill, William
      - 3 ALS to C.W.M. Kent, 1900-10 (Box 2, Folder 92)
    - Hussey, Sadie
      - ALS to "Marianne", 1892 Aug 29 (Box 2, Folder 93)
        Concerning an invitation
    - J., H. E
      - ALS to "dear friend;" St. Johns Hill, 1831 Oct 4 (Box 2, Folder 94)
    - Manning, Henry Edward, 1808-1892
      - ALS to his mother; Lavington, 1847 May 11 (Box 2, Folder 95)
        With ALS from Mrs. Manning to him, 12 May 1847, and note in Manning's hand concerning his mother's death. With envelopes annotated by Manning.
    - Moncrieff-Smyth, C. J.
      - ALS to Father Kent; 53 Kensington Gardens, 1905 Jun 26 (Box 2, Folder 96)
        Concerning autographs of Cardinal Manning. With envelope.
    - O'Kelly de Galway, A.
      - ALS to the Duke of Norfolk; Paris, 1900 Jan 8 (Box 2, Folder 97)
        Concerning the copying of genealogical documents. In French.
      - "Polly" and "Charlie" to "Mamma" (Box 2, Folder 98)
- Writings, 1847-1898; Series II; 0.4; (1 box)
  Series II, Writings, is organized into two subseries. The first is arranged alphabetically by title, and the second is arranged alphabetically by type of material and then by title.
  - BOOKS AND PAMPHLETS
    - Aletheia, or, the Doom of Mythology
      - Review: newspaper clipping, 1850 Aug 31 (Box 3, Folder 99)
    - Corona Catholica
      - Advertisements, [1880] (Box 3, Folder 100)
      - Announcements, [1880] (Box 3, Folder 101)
      - Dedicatory prayer to Leo XIII, [1880] (Box 3, Folder 102)
        Holograph in English and printed Latin version With bilingual draft versions, holograph
      - Dummy, [1879?] (Box 3, Folder 103)
        Holograph
      - "Epigram on the acession of Leo the Thirteenth. Latin Version", n.d. (Box 3, Folder 104)
      - "Fragments of MS about the Corona Catholica", n.d. (Box 3, Folder 105)
        Holographs and clippings
      - List of contributors, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 106)
        Notebook and typescript
      - List of languages of contributions, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 107)
      - List of presentation copy recipients, 1880 (Box 3, Folder 108)
      - Notebook containing lists of solicitations for contributions and support (Box 3, Folder 109)
      - Notes on St. Malachy's Prophecy, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 110)
      - Reviews and responses, 1881, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 111)
    - The Humour and Pathos of Charles Dickens
      - Printed copy of Prefatory Note, 1883 (Box 3, Folder 112)
    - Leigh Hunt as Poet and Essayist
      - Page proof set, corrected and dated, 1888 (Box 3, Folder 113-115)
    - The Life of Charles Lamb
      - Printer's instructions, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 116)
      - Sales figures, 1893, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 117)
    - Poems (1870)
      - Page proof sheets, marked "1st proof, 14/3/70", 1870 (Box 3, Folder 118)
        Incomplete
      - Page proof sheets, marked "1st revise, 21/3/70", 1870 (Box 3, Folder 119)
      - Page proof sheets, marked "2nd proof, 21/3/70", 1870 (Box 3, Folder 120-121)
    - Thirty of the Grand Old Latin Poems from the Roman Breviary
      - Typescripts of title page and table of contents (Box 3, Folder 122)
      - Typescript of translation of "Dies Irae", n.d. (Box 3, Folder 123)
      - Printed copy of translation of "Salve Regina", 1879 Oct 4 (Box 3, Folder 124)
      - Printed copy of translation of "Ave Regina Coelorum", 1879 Nov 29 (Box 3, Folder 125)
      - Notes on copies posted, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 126)
  - SHORTER WORKS
    - Articles
      - "Death of the Prince of Wales", 1871 Dec
        Proof printing of obituary notice on the expected death of Albert Edward, Prince of Wales (later Edward VII)
      - "The Duke of Wellington on Catholic Loyalty", n.d. (Box 3, Folder 127)
        Proof sheet, corrected
      - "Edgar Allen Poe", [1898?] (Box 3, Folder 128)
        Holograph With: rejection letter from William Blackwood, 1899 Jan 12
      - "Edward Bulwer, Lord Lytton As I Knew Him", 1898 (Box 3, Folder 129)
        Page proof of introduction and bibliography of Lytton's works
      - "Letter to the Saturday Review, [1869] (Box 3, Folder 130)
        Holograph draft, corrected
      - "Reminiscences of Chelsea in the '70s and Early '80s" (Box 3, Folder 131)
        Typescript, corrected
      - "An Unpublished Letter by M. de Lamartine", [1869 Mar] (Box 3, Folder 132)
        Printed copies
    - Poems
      - "An Autumm Thought", n.d. (Box 3, Folder 133)
        Holograph With pressed leaves
      - "The Dying Bridegroom", n.d. (Box 3, Folder 134)
      - "Goethe's Statue at Munich", n.d. (Box 3, Folder 135)
      - "An Informal Invitation", 1886 Jan (Box 3, Folder 136)
        Holograph, corrected
      - "Longfellow in England" (Box 3, Folder 137)
        Offprint of poem that appeared in 1868 in the London Times
      - "Prayer: From the French of H. E. J.", n.d. (Box 3, Folder 138)
        Holograph, signed
      - "Raphael's 'Madonna di San Sisto'", [ca. 1874] (Box 3, Folder 139)
        Typescript, typescript corrected and typescript carbons
      - "Salome. As Seen on the 10th of December 1869 in William Story's Studio in Rome", n.d. (Box 3, Folder 139)
      - "The Judgement of St. Gudule (November 1869 Brussels)", n.d. (Box 3, Folder 140)
    - Reviews
      - "Mr. Tennyson's New Poems: The Princess. A Medley ", [1847] (Box 3, Folder 141)
- Personal Papers, 1783-1902; Series III; 0.81; (2 boxes)
  Series III, Personal Papers, is organized into alphabetically arranged subseries which are themselves alphabetically arranged by folder title.
  - ARTWORK
    - Caricature by E. L. Blanchard, 1875 Jul 23 (Box 4, Folder 142)
      Inscribed to CK
    - Caricature print, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 143)
    - Flag of the House of Savoy and coat of arms of the Vatican (Box 4, Folder 144)
    - Flowers: watercolor, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 145)
    - Silhouette, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 146)
  - BIOGRAPHICAL INFORMATION
    - Announcement of CK's purchase of The Sun, 1862 Dec 22 (Box 4, Folder 147)
    - Biographical sketch, incomplete, accompanied by solicitation letter from Men and Women of Our Time, 1894 (Box 4, Folder 148)
    - Cancelled checks, 1860-98 (Box 4, Folder 149)
    - "Chronological list of my publishers", 1898 (Box 4, Folder 150)
      Typescript
    - Election returns for Derby, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 151)
      Holograph notes on returns for CK's candidate for MP
    - Marriage certificate of CK and Ann Young (notarized copy dated), 1902 Mar 27 (Box 4, Folder 152)
    - Memberships
      - Athenaeum Club, 1881, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 153)
      - Institute of Journalists, 1893 Sep 4 (Box 4, Folder 154)
      - Primrose League certificate, 1885 Nov 2 (Box 4, Folder 155)
    - "Novelists I Have Known", n.d. (Box 4, Folder 156)
      Typescript carbon
    - Obituary notice for CK (2 copies), [1902] (Box 4, Folder 157)
    - Papers Relating to Ann Young Kent
      - Account of sales of Evelyn Stuart, 1857 Jun 1 (Box 4, Folder 158)
      - Life insurance policy for Ann Young Kent, 1901 Nov 26 (Box 4, Folder 159)
        See also: Oversize, Box 6, folder 229
      - "Old Wrongs Ferguson!", n.d. (Box 4, Folder 160)
        Holograph, incomplete
      - "Old Play Bills", n.d. (Box 4, Folder 161)
      - "Synopsis", n.d. (Box 4, Folder 162)
        Typescript of story outline
    - School examination schedule: Prior Park, 1836 (Box 4, Folder 163)
      With note to "my dearest Papa" by CK
    - School examination schedule: Oscott College, 1838 (Box 4, Folder 164)
    - Testimonial letters for CK, 1870 Nov (Box 4, Folder 165-167)
      Copies in CK's hand of 14 letters written to support his candidacy for an editorship. Authors included: Charles Dickens, Jr.; Lord Lytton; Sir Henry Bulwer; George Routledge; Samuel Warren; William Longman; John Forster; and John Blackwood. Accompamied by copy of CK's letter to the "Committee," and an envelope listing the authors of the letters.
    - Testimonials to CK, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 168)
      Typescripts and typescripts carbon of favorable comments on CK
  - FAMILY PAPERS
    - Advertisement for Edward Kent, "humorous songs and sketches at the piano" (3 copies) (Box 4, Folder 169)
    - Commission of William Kent as Fourth Lieutenant of the Blenheim, 1783 May 17
      Parchment, signed by Keppel, Duncannon and Townshend
    - Genealogical notes and notes on early Australian history (Box 4, Folder 170)
    - Genealogical notes, unidentified, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 171)
    - Marriage certificate of Murdo Young and Katherine Ross (notarized copy dated), 1902 Aug 15 (Box 4, Folder 172)
    - "Memorandum for the private information of the family", 1817 Dec 14 (Box 4, Folder 173)
      List of family members with birth dates and birth places
    - "Monthly returns of Capt. Wm. Kent's stock from 7th May to 7th December 1810", 1810 Dec
    - Newspaper clipping concerning Col. William Kent, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 174)
    - "Promissory note for Calcutta sicca rupees....", 1811 Jun 30 (Box 4, Folder 175)
      Made out to William Kent
    - "State of the case of Widow Baggs...", 1822 Sep (Box 4, Folder 176)
      Concerning financial situation of Kent's grandmother
    - Will of Auguste-Louis Josse with translation and notes, 1827-40 (Box 4, Folder 177)
      Concerns a bequest to William Kent
  - JOURNALS AND NOTEBOOKS
    - Diary, 1892 (Box 4, Folder 178)
      Account of daily activities, kept in a "Charles Lett's Improved Diary" With several newspaper clippings and a memorandum in shorthand
    - Journal of a Six-week Tour, 1869 Nov-Dec (Box 4, Folder 179)
      Narrative account of CK's journey to Rome to attend Vatican I. Included are CK's impressions of the work of the Council; accounts of interviews with journalists in Brussels, Cologne, Berlin, Trieste, Florence, Rome and Paris; descriptions of meetings with individuals including Cardinal Manning; Thomas A. Trollope, Charles Fuller, and William Wetmore Story; and details of sightseeing expeditions.
    - Miniature notebooks, n.d. (Box 4, Folder 180)
      Containing accounts, lists of saints' days, French vocabulary lessons and other material
  - MEMORABILIA AND OTHER PAPERS
    - Admission to the Middle Temple of Thomas Moore, 1795 Nov (Box 5, Folder 181)
    - Address label for Galignani's Messenger, stamped, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 182)
    - Document issued by the Commune de Paris, 1871 May 11 (Box 5, Folder 183)
      Authorizes the bearer ---cott? to negotiate the exchange of "citoyen Blanqui" [Louis-Auguste Blanqui] for "citoyen Darboy" [Georges Darboy, Archbishop of Paris] Signed by Viard, Chardon, Cournet; stamped by four departments of the Commune.
    - "Leigh Hunt:" transcripts of an inscription to CK and of his poem "The Nile" (Box 5, Folder 184)
      With: newspaper clipping of letter to the editor on Hunt by Alfred Ainger
    - "Memoranda, C.K." (Box 5, Folder 185)
      Envelope containing miscellaneous clippings and notes
    - Memorial to William Ewart Gladstone, [1882] (Box 5, Folder 186)
      Petition for Compassionate Relief funding for the 92 year old former actress Frances Maria Kelly
    - "Novena to Our Lady of Lourdes", n.d. (Box 5, Folder 187)
    - "Orton's Lines addressed to me", n.d. (Box 5, Folder 188)
      2 manuscript poems, "Poetical Brotherhood" and "To My Friend of Friends, C.W.K", 1869, n.d.
    - "Scene from The Briton, by Phillips", n.d. (Box 5, Folder 189)
      Copy in CK's hand
    - "Some music saved from the burning of Covent Garden Theater 4 March 1856" (Box 5, Folder 190)
    - "Ticket for the British Museum", 1879 Mar 12 (Box 5, Folder 191)
  - PHOTOGRAPHS
    - Bowden, Henry Sebastian, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 192)
      Inscribed: "Sebastian Bowden"
    - Gladstone, William, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 193)
    - "Nouvelle église paroissiale de Lourdes", 1876 (Box 5, Folder 194)
      Inscribed to CK by Abbé Peyramale, parish priest of Lourdes and supporter of Bernadette Soubirous, 1876 Jun 30
    - Warren, Samuel, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 195)
      Damaged; inscribed to CK
    - Unidentified man, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 196)
  - PRINTED MATERIAL
    - Advertisements and tickets, 1886-93, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 197)
    - Calendar, 1880 (Box 5, Folder 198)
    - Calling cards, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 199)
    - "Chambers's Papers for the People: Ancient Rites and Mysteries" (Box 5, Folder 200)
    - Coat of arms of a Cardinal, with motto "Tales ambio defensores", n.d. (Box 5, Folder 201)
    - Coat of arms of Leo XIII, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 202)
    - Greeting cards, 1901, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 203)
    - Holy cards, 1893-1902 (Box 5, Folder 204)
    - "Lenten Services 1902" (Box 5, Folder 205)
    - Menu for the United Club Annual Dinner, 1891 Jul 15 (Box 5, Folder 206)
    - Newspaper clippings
      - Charles Dickens, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 207)
      - Death of the Earl of Beaconsfield [Benjamin Disraeli], 1881 (Box 5, Folder 208-211)
      - Lord Lytton's appointment to the Viceroyalty of India, 1876 Jan (Box 5, Folder 212)
      - Obituaries and funeral notices, 1875-77, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 213)
    - Newspapers
      - The Bombay Catholic Examiner, 1880 May 22
      - L'osservatore Romano, 1880 Apr 29
    - Photolithographs
      - Letter and inscription by Robert Browning (Box 5, Folder 214)
      - Letter by William Gladstone, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 215)
      - Letter by Cardinal Manning, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 216)
    - Poems
      - "A Message to the Young Cricketers of the Infant Orphan Asylum", n.d. (Box 5, Folder 217)
      - "In Loving Memory of Edward Lawless...." (2 copies), 1897 Feb 15 (Box 5, Folder 218)
    - Posters
      - "Holbeach Turnpike Special Meeting", 1849 Apr 3
      - "Vote for Borthwick", n.d. (Box 5, Folder 219)
    - "Presented with The Craftsman, May 1884:" "photoink" portraits of Algernon Borthwick and W. H. Fisher
    - "St. Felix", n.d. (Box 5, Folder 220)
      Annotated by CK
  - RESEARCH MATERIAL
    - Library call slips, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 221)
    - Lists, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 222)
    - Notes on bibliography and references (Box 5, Folder 223)
    - Notes on Demosthenes and on classical historians (Box 5, Folder 224)
    - Notes on the Dukes of Norfolk, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 225)
      See also: Oversize, Box 6, folder 236
    - Other notes, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 226-227)
- Oversize, 1.67; (1 box)
  - "Death of the Prince of Wales", 1871 Dec (Box 6, Folder 228)
  - Life insurance policy for Ann Kent, 1902 Aug 20 (Box 6, Folder 229)
  - Commission of William Kent, 1783 May 17 (Box 6, Folder 230)
  - Stock account, 1810 Dec (Box 6, Folder 231)
  - Bombay Catholic Examiner, 1880 May 22 (Box 6, Folder 232)
  - L'osservatore Romano, 1880 Apr 29 (Box 6, Folder 233)
  - Holbeach Turnpike poster, 1849 Apr 3 (Box 6, Folder 234)
  - Presented with the Craftsman poster, 1884 May (Box 6, Folder 235)
  - Genealogical chart, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 236)